Finding Aid for the Donald A. Glaser Papers, 1943-2013, bulk 1949-2003 GlaserDA
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
Donald A. Glaser Papers
1918-2016
1949-2003
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
Glaser, Donald Arthur
GlaserDA
15.97 linear feet 41 boxes (Caltech Collection); 17 cartons (UC Berkeley Collection)
Donald Arthur Glaser (1926–2013) earned his PhD in Physics and Mathematics from the California Institute of Technology in 1950 and won the 1960 Nobel Prize in Physics for his invention of the bubble chamber. He then changed his research focus to molecular biology and went on to co-found Cetus Corporation, the first biotechnology company. In the 1980s he again switched his focus to neurobiology and the visual system. The Donald A. Glaser papers consist of research notes and notebooks, manuscripts and printed papers, correspondence, awards, biographical material, photographs, audio-visual material, and born-digital files. This finding aid is an intellectual arrangement of two collections: first portion originally from the University of California Berkeley, Bancroft Library and the second from the Caltech Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection has been fully digitized and can be accessed at Donald A. Glaser Papers. For physical access to the papers, requests must be submitted in writing. The UC Berkeley portion is stored offsite.
General
The University of California, Berkeley and Caltech Donald A. Glaser Papers were acquired separately and the ownership of the collections remain with the two institutions. This collection guide intellectually combines the two collections. The UC Berkeley portion of the Donald Glaser Papers are on an indefinite loan to the Caltech Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Caltech Collection: The Donald A. Glaser papers were generously given to the Caltech Archives by Lynn Glaser in 2015. Berkeley Collection: The Donald Glaser papers were gifted to the Bancroft Library by Donald Glaser in 2007.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Arthur Glaser was born on September 21, 1926 in Cleveland, Ohio. He received his B.S. in Physics and Mathematics from the Case School of Applied Science in 1946, and a PhD in Physics and Mathematics in 1950 from the California Institute of Technology where Nobel Laureate Carl Anderson was his advisor. He joined the faculty at the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor in 1949 where his interest in elementary particles led to the invention of the bubble chamber in 1953. Glaser moved to UC Berkeley in 1959 and in 1960, at the age of 34, won the Nobel Prize in Physics. Shortly after he moved to Berkeley, his research shifted to automated experimentation in molecular and cell biology. He worked in UC Berkeley's Virus Lab, conducting experiments with bacteria and bacterial viruses called phages and mammalian cells. He designed automated equipment that made it easier to grow these cells and to study how they grow, repair themselves, and reproduce. His work in this area led to cofounding one of the first biotechnology companies and eventually to Cetus Corporation. Glaser shifted his research interests toward neuroscience and the visual system by 1981 and continued work in this field into the 2000s. Glaser passed away on February 28, 2013.
Arrangement
The letter B or C in the box identifier indicates ownership by Berkeley or Caltech, respectively.
Physics; Bubble Chambers; Nobel Prize winners; Molecular biology; Neuroscience; Manuscript Collection
- Series 1 Biographical and Personal, 1910s-2016; 1
  - Subseries 1 Family material, 1943-2007
    - Cleveland Heights High School, 1943-1983; GlaserDA_01_01_01C_01 (Box C-1.1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Correspondence, grades, alumni material
    - Louise and William Glaser items, 1973; 1989; GlaserDA_01_01_01C_02 (Box C-1.1, Folder 2)
    - Glaser family tree and reunion materials, 1990-2003; GlaserDA_01_01_01C_03; CD included (Box C-1.1, Folder 3)
    - Letter for sister Evie's memorial, 2007; GlaserDA_01_01_01C_04 (Box C-1.1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2 Journal entries and notes, 1950s-2004
    - European travelogues, ca. 1950s; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_05 (Box C-1.1, Folder 5)
    - Journal entries and schedules, 1958; 1964; 1969; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_06 (Box C-1.1, Folder 6)
    - MIT notebook I, 1961-1962; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_07 (Box C-1.1, Folder 7)
    - MIT notebook II, 1962; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_08 (Box C-1.1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, messages, and to-do lists, 1974-1996; 2003-2004; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_09 (Box C-1.1, Folder 9)
    - Journal entries - Scientific interests, 1979-1981; GlaserDA_01_02_01C_10 (Box C-1.1, Folder 10)
      Related to theoretical biology
  - Subseries 3 Job search and appointments, 1951-1984
    - Job applications, 1951-1957; GlaserDA_01_03_02B_29 (Box B-1.2, Folder 29)
    - Offers and correspondence, 1956-1961; GlaserDA_01_03_01C_11 (Box C-1.1, Folder 11)
    - UC job acceptance, 1959; GlaserDA_01_03_17B_09 (Box B-1.17, Folder 9)
    - MIT - Visiting professorship correspondence, 1961 April 18 - 1962 May 22; GlaserDA_01_03_01C_12 (Box C-1.1, Folder 12)
    - Miller Research Professorship, 1982-1984; GlaserDA_01_03_13B_13 (Box B-1.13, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 4 Biographical write ups and interviews, 1975-2012
    - IBM Vail Conference biographical statement, 1975; GlaserDA_01_04_01C_13 (Box C-1.1, Folder 13)
    - Charlan Nemeth interviews with Glaser for unpublished book, 1990-2012; GlaserDA_01_04_01C_14 (Box C-1.1, Folder 14)
      Interviews conducted 1993
    - Eric Vettel Oral History interview material, 2004-2005; GlaserDA_01_04_01C_15 (Box C-1.1, Folder 15)
    - Donald A. Glaser book interviews material, ca. 2010; GlaserDA_01_04_01C_16 (Box C-1.1, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 5 Correspondence, 1949-2014
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_21 (Box B-1.16, Folder 21)
      Includes congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize award
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_22 (Box B-1.16, Folder 22)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_23 (Box B-1.16, Folder 23)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_24 (Box B-1.16, Folder 24)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_17B_01 (Box B-1.17, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949-1969; GlaserDA_01_05_17B_02 (Box B-1.17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with S.A. Goudsmit, 1953-1955; GlaserDA_01_05_02B_04 (Box B-1.2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with R.P. Shutt, 1954-1955; GlaserDA_01_05_02B_05 (Box B-1.2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1954-1963; GlaserDA_01_05_02B_03 (Box B-1.2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with David C. Rahm, 1955; GlaserDA_01_05_02B_06 (Box B-1.2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, misc. - A, 1969-2004; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_01 (Box C-1.2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, misc. - B, 1976-2006; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_02 (Box C-1.2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, misc. - C, 1949-1996; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_03 (Box C-1.2, Folder 3)
      Includes 1949 Caltech Christmas card; Owen Chamberlain; F.H.C. Crick
    - Correspondence, misc. - D, 1970-2002; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_04 (Box C-1.2, Folder 4)
      Includes letter from Max Delbrueck
    - Correspondence, misc. - E, 1978-2002; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_05 (Box C-1.2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, misc. - F, 1960-1991; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_06 (Box C-1.2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, misc. - G, 1988-2014; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_07 (Box C-1.2, Folder 7)
      Includes letter from Murray Gell-Mann
    - Correspondence, misc. - H, 1975-2000; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_08 (Box C-1.2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, misc. - I, J, 1978; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_09 (Box C-1.2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, misc. - K, 1975-1991; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_10 (Box C-1.2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, misc. - L, 1961-1992; GlaserDA_01_05_02C_11 (Box C-1.2, Folder 11)
      Includes letter from Joshua Lederberg
    - Correspondence, misc. - M, 1964-1991; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_01 (Box C-1.3, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Paul MacCready; Ed McMillan
    - Correspondence, misc. - N, O, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_02 (Box C-1.3, Folder 2)
      Puzzle game from Frank Oppenheimer
    - Correspondence, misc. - P, 1982-1995; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_03 (Box C-1.3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, misc. - R, 1986-1994; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_04 (Box C-1.3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, misc. - S, 1976-2004; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_05 (Box C-1.3, Folder 5)
      Includes letter from Oliver Sacks; Gunther Stent
    - Correspondence, misc. - T, 1975-1988; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_06 (Box C-1.3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, misc. - U, V, 1976-1981; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_07 (Box C-1.3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, misc. - W, 1979-1992; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_08 (Box C-1.3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, misc. - Z, 1984-1986; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_09 (Box C-1.3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, misc. - Unidentified, 1981-1992; GlaserDA_01_05_03C_10 (Box C-1.3, Folder 10)
    - "Crackpot" letters, 1972-1978; GlaserDA_01_05_06B_02 (Box B-1.6, Folder 2)
    - "Crackpot" letters, 1983-1987; GlaserDA_01_05_12B_05 (Box B-1.12, Folder 5)
    - "Crackpot" letters, 1990-1996; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_20 (Box B-1.14, Folder 20)
    - Ronald Gruber, 1979-1983; GlaserDA_01_05_12B_28 (Box B-1.12, Folder 28)
    - Garrett Odell, 1980-1982; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_25 (Box B-1.13, Folder 25)
    - Joshua Zeevi, 1980-1988; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_09 (Box B-1.14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_14 (Box B-1.11, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_15 (Box B-1.11, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_16 (Box B-1.11, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_17 (Box B-1.11, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_18 (Box B-1.11, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_19 (Box B-1.11, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_20 (Box B-1.11, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_21 (Box B-1.11, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_22 (Box B-1.11, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_23 (Box B-1.11, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_24 (Box B-1.11, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_25 (Box B-1.11, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_26 (Box B-1.11, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_27 (Box B-1.11, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_11B_28 (Box B-1.11, Folder 28)
    - Autograph requests, ca. 1980-1995; GlaserDA_01_05_17B_04 (Box B-1.17, Folder 4)
    - Autograph requests, ca. 1980-1995; GlaserDA_01_05_17B_05 (Box B-1.17, Folder 5)
    - Edwin H. Land, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_05 (Box B-1.13, Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_11 (Box B-1.13, Folder 11)
    - Max-Planck Institute, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_12 (Box B-1.13, Folder 12)
    - Photography, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_27 (Box B-1.13, Folder 27)
    - Leona Marshall Libby, 1982-1983; GlaserDA_01_05_13B_07 (Box B-1.13, Folder 7)
    - Vatican, 1983-1989; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_02 (Box B-1.14, Folder 2)
    - Semir Zeki, 1984-1985; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_10 (Box B-1.14, Folder 10)
    - Richard Voss, 1987; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_04 (Box B-1.14, Folder 4)
    - Antonio Zichichi, 1988-1990; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_14 (Box B-1.16, Folder 14)
    - Weizmann Institute, 1990; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_12 (Box B-1.16, Folder 12)
    - Fang Li Zhi, 1990-1991; GlaserDA_01_05_16B_13 (Box B-1.16, Folder 13)
    - Guggenheim Memorial, 1990-1993; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_30 (Box B-1.14, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1994; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_18 (Box B-1.14, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1994; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_19 (Box B-1.14, Folder 19)
    - Electronic mail, 1995; GlaserDA_01_05_14B_25 (Box B-1.14, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 6 Nobel Prize, 1960-2004
    This subseries contains the bulk of Glaser's Nobel Prize material, including reception items and ephemera, clippings, and photographs from his 1960 trip. Nobel events occurring after 1960 are also represented.
    - Nobel trip - Itinerary, money deposit, Rootes Motors Limited correspondence, 1960 December - 1961 February; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_01 (Box C-1.4, Folder 1)
    - Nobel reception items, 1960 December; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_02; Notecards, menus, programs, invitations (Box C-1.4, Folder 2)
    - Nobel lecture "Elementary Particles and Bubble Chambers", 1960 December 12; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_03 (Box C-1.4, Folder 3)
    - Nobel trip - Miscellaneous items - Sweden, 1960 December; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_04 (Box C-1.4, Folder 4)
    - Nobel and wedding related articles, 1960-1961; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_05 (Box C-1.4, Folder 5)
    - Nobel related Swedish articles I, 1960 December 4-10; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_06 (Box C-1.4, Folder 6)
      Language: Swedish
    - Nobel related Swedish articles II, 1960 December 11; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_07 (Box C-1.4, Folder 7)
    - Nobel related Swedish articles III, 1960 December 12-18; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_08 (Box C-1.4, Folder 8)
    - Nobel trip Danish articles and items, 1960-1961; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_09 (Box C-1.4, Folder 9)
      Language: Danish
    - Time-Life Men of the Year, 1960-1961; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_10 (Box C-1.4, Folder 10)
    - Telegrams (mostly congratulations on Nobel Prize), ca. 1960; GlaserDA_01_06_17B_03 (Box B-1.17, Folder 3)
    - White House dinner for Nobel Prize winners, 1962 April; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_11; Invitation, articles (Box C-1.4, Folder 11)
    - MIT Science Reporter - Interview transcript, ca. 1962; GlaserDA_01_06_04C_12 (Box C-1.4, Folder 12)
    - Nobel trip personal photo album, 1960-1967; GlaserDA_01_06_05C_01 (Box C-1.5, Folder 1)
    - Nobel Foundation photographs and correspondence, 1960 December -1961 February; GlaserDA_01_06_05C_02 (Box C-1.5, Folder 2)
    - Nobel reception photographs, 1960 December; GlaserDA_01_06_05C_03 (Box C-1.5, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Nobel related articles - 1970s, 1973-1976; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_01 (Box C-1.6, Folder 1)
    - UC Berkeley's Nobel laureates, 1969; 1974; 1981; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_02; Photographs and memos (Box C-1.6, Folder 2)
      Includes photograph from Edwin McMillan's retirement dinner
    - Nobel 75th Anniversary, 1976; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_03; Memo, photographs, article (Box C-1.6, Folder 3)
      Glaser not pictured
    - Nobel related correspondence - Endorsements, petitions, solicitations, 1977-1999; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_04 (Box C-1.6, Folder 4)
    - Nobel related, 1979-1983; GlaserDA_01_06_13B_23 (Box B-1.13, Folder 23)
    - Glaser correspondence to 1980 Physics and Chemistry Nobel winners, 1980 October; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_05 (Box C-1.6, Folder 5)
    - Pioneers of Science: Nobel Prize Winners in Physics: Donald Arthur Glaser, 1980; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_06 (Box C-1.6, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Nobel related articles - 1980s, 1980-1987; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_07 (Box C-1.6, Folder 7)
    - Food and Disarmament International, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_01_06_12B_19 (Box B-1.12, Folder 19)
    - Nuclear arms, 1981-1983; GlaserDA_01_06_13B_24 (Box B-1.13, Folder 24)
    - Nobel Prize winners lists and announcements, 1982; 1988; 1992; 1993; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_08 (Box C-1.6, Folder 8)
    - Giovannella portraits of Nobel laureates, 1983-1988; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_09; 35mm slides (Box C-1.6, Folder 9)
    - Nobel Laureates of the Bay Area - Articles and correspondence, 1984-1985; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_10 (Box C-1.6, Folder 10)
    - Yuan T. Lee Nobel laureate reception - Photos and related articles, 1986-1987; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_11 (Box C-1.6, Folder 11)
    - American Nobel Anniversary Committee, 1986-1987; GlaserDA_01_06_10B_40 (Box B-1.10, Folder 40)
    - The Nobel Tradition at Berkeley, 1986 (Box C-1.6, Folder 12)
    - Washington-New York (Nobel Laureate Dinner), 1987; GlaserDA_01_06_14B_05 (Box B-1.14, Folder 5)
    - World Future Society, 1987; GlaserDA_01_06_14B_08 (Box B-1.14, Folder 8)
    - American Nobel Committee correspondence, 1988; 1990; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_13 (Box C-1.6, Folder 13)
    - World Congress Alternatives and Environment, 1988-1989; GlaserDA_01_06_14B_07 (Box B-1.14, Folder 7)
    - Nobel Jubilee 1991 - Correspondence, 1989-1991; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_14 (Box C-1.6, Folder 14)
    - Endorsement, 1990; GlaserDA_01_06_14B_26 (Box B-1.14, Folder 26)
    - Nobel Jubilee 1991 - Itineraries, programs, invitations, photographs, 1991 December; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_15 (Box C-1.6, Folder 15)
    - The Nobel Century - Correspondence, 1990 October - 1991 January; GlaserDA_01_06_06C_16 (Box C-1.6, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Nobel related articles - 1990s, 1991-1998; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_01 (Box C-1.7, Folder 1)
    - The Science Coalition - Federal funding of university based research, 1996 June - September; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_02 (Box C-1.7, Folder 2)
    - American Physical Society Centenary Celebration, 1996; 1999; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_03 (Box C-1.7, Folder 3)
    - Smithsonian exhibit - Nobel Laureates, 1997 March; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_04 (Box C-1.7, Folder 4)
    - Fellowship of the Institute of Physics, 1998-1999; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_05 (Box C-1.7, Folder 5)
    - Nobel Conference at Gustavus Adolphus College, 1999; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_06 (Box C-1.7, Folder 6)
    - Nobel related correspondence - Endorsements, petitions, solicitations - 2000s, 2000-2002; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_07 (Box C-1.7, Folder 7)
    - Nobel related articles - 2000s, 2009; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_08 (Box C-1.7, Folder 8)
      Articles in German and Italian
    - California Nobel Prize Centennial, 2000 June - 2001 October; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_09 (Box C-1.7, Folder 9)
    - Berkeley's Nobel Tradition - Centenary Celebration of E.O. Lawrence, 2001 October; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_10 (Box C-1.7, Folder 10)
    - Nobel Prize 100th Anniversary stamps, 2001; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_11 (Box C-1.7, Folder 11)
    - Nobel Prize Centennial 1901-2001: Laureate Stamps & Inscriptions exhibition invitation, GlaserDA_01_06_07C_12 (Box C-1.7, Folder 12)
    - Nobel Prize Centennial 1901-2001, 2001 December; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_13 (Box C-1.7, Folder 13)
    - Committee for the Meetings of Nobel Laureates in Lindau, 2001-2007; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_14; DVD, nametag (Box C-1.7, Folder 14)
    - Monument honoring American Nobel laureates - from Consulate General of Sweden in New York, 2002 April 28; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_15 (Box C-1.7, Folder 15)
    - Telegraph Avenue Banners flyer - Saluting UC Berkeley's 18 Nobel Laureates, 2003 April 11; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_16 (Box C-1.7, Folder 16)
    - Nobel Online Biography edit, 2004; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_17 (Box C-1.7, Folder 17)
    - Berkeley Daily Planet article re: Glaser's endorsement of John Kerry, 2004 June; GlaserDA_01_06_07C_18 (Box C-1.7, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 7 Other awards and honors, 1958-2000
    - U.S. Junior Chamber of Commerce - Ten Outstanding Young Men honor, 1958, 1958 December 19; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_01; Telegram (Box C-1.8, Folder 1)
    - TOYM Award, 1958-1960; GlaserDA_01_07_05B_06 (Box B-1.5, Folder 6)
    - Regents of the University of California - Certificate of Esteem, 1960 December; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_02; Certificate (Box C-1.8, Folder 2)
    - Berkeley Junior Chamber of Commerce - Certificate of Excellence, 1961 January; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_03; Certificate (Box C-1.8, Folder 3)
    - Franklin Institute - Elliot Cresson Medal Award, 1961 October; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_04; Programs, correspondence, photograph (Box C-1.8, Folder 4)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science - Fellow certificate, 1962 May; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_05; Certificate, programs (Box C-1.8, Folder 5)
    - Commercial Development Association - Certificate of Appreciation, 1963; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_06; Certificate (Box C-1.8, Folder 6)
    - Caltech Alumni Distinguished Service Award, 1966 October 25; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_07; Certificate (Box C-1.8, Folder 7)
    - National Academy of Sciences membership rosette, 1978 December; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_08; Rosette (Box C-1.8, Folder 8)
    - Cleveland Heights, 1981-1982; GlaserDA_01_07_11B_09 (Box B-1.11, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Academy of Arts and Sciences 60th Convocation - Fellow certificate, 1986 December; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_09; Certificate, correspondence (Box C-1.8, Folder 9)
    - American Physical Society Fellow's pin, ca. 2000; GlaserDA_01_07_08C_10; Pin (Box C-1.8, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 8 Photographs, 1910s-2005
    - Family photos, ca. 1918-2000; Six images from USB drive (Box C-1.9, Folder 1)
    - Early class photos, ca. 1935; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_02 (Box C-1.9, Folder 2)
    - College photos, 1944-1949; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_03 (Box C-1.9, Folder 3)
    - Portraits, lab, and event photos, 1950-2005; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_04 (Box C-1.9, Folder 4)
    - Russian Physics Meeting in Moscow, ca. 1956; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_05 (Box C-1.9, Folder 5)
    - Music photos, ca. 1960s-1970; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_06 (Box C-1.9, Folder 6)
    - Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago - slides and correspondence, 1982; 2006; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_07 (Box C-1.9, Folder 7)
    - UC LEADS & Pass the Torch Programs photos, 2005 November; GlaserDA_01_08_09C_08 (Box C-1.9, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 9 Miscellaneous material, 1948-2016
    This subseries includes general publications and talks, event ephemera, symphony patent documents, and sheet music.
    - Notes, unknown subjects, undated; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_09 (Box C-1.9, Folder 9)
    - Travel, 1948-1959; GlaserDA_01_09_05B_07 (Box B-1.5, Folder 7)
    - Travel, 1948-1959; GlaserDA_01_09_05B_08 (Box B-1.5, Folder 8)
    - Languages, 1958; GlaserDA_01_09_03B_06 (Box B-1.3, Folder 6)
    - Biographical and bibliographical files, 1960-1990; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_15 (Box B-1.16, Folder 15)
    - Biographical and bibliographical files, 1960-1990; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_16 (Box B-1.16, Folder 16)
    - Biographical and bibliographical files, 1960-1990; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_17 (Box B-1.16, Folder 17)
    - Biographical and bibliographical files, 1960-1990; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_18 (Box B-1.16, Folder 18)
    - Biographical and bibliographical files, 1960-1990; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_19 (Box B-1.16, Folder 19)
    - Articles and clippings, 1961-1998; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_10 (Box C-1.9, Folder 10)
      Not featuring Glaser
    - Events and related material, 1963-2005; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_11 (Box C-1.9, Folder 11)
      Flyers, invitations, programs
    - Sierra Club, 1967-1970; GlaserDA_01_09_17B_11 (Box B-1.17, Folder 11)
    - Sierra Club, 1967-1970; GlaserDA_01_09_17B_12 (Box B-1.17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous publications featuring Glaser, 1977-2007; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_12 (Box C-1.9, Folder 12)
    - Glaser talks and related material, 1977-2008; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_13 (Box C-1.9, Folder 13)
      Includes notes, flyers, correspondence
    - Exploratorium Board Meetings, 1980-1984; GlaserDA_01_09_12B_12 (Box B-1.12, Folder 12)
    - Exploratorium Board Meetings, 1980-1984; GlaserDA_01_09_12B_13 (Box B-1.12, Folder 13)
    - Exploratorium Board Meetings, 1980-1984; GlaserDA_01_09_12B_14 (Box B-1.12, Folder 14)
    - Journals, 1981-1984; GlaserDA_01_09_13B_03 (Box B-1.13, Folder 3)
    - List of publications, 1982; GlaserDA_01_09_16B_20 (Box B-1.16, Folder 20)
    - Richard Garwin, 1983; GlaserDA_01_09_12B_22 (Box B-1.12, Folder 22)
    - Watercraft, 1983; GlaserDA_01_09_14B_06 (Box B-1.14, Folder 6)
    - Memorials and obituaries, 1984-2007; GlaserDA_01_09_09C_14 (Box C-1.9, Folder 14)
      Colleagues and contemporaries
    - Permission to publish, 1988-1994; GlaserDA_01_09_15B_23 (Box B-1.15, Folder 23)
    - Symphony patent I, 1999; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_01 (Box C-1.10, Folder 1)
    - Symphony patent II, 2000; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_02 (Box C-1.10, Folder 2)
    - Symphony patent III, 2001; GlaserDA_01_09_10C_03 (Box C-1.10, Folder 3)